Kwabena Ampah

+233554602954 | ampahkwabena5@gmail.com | Accra, Ghana

SUMMARY

Analytical Software Developer with 4-year background in software design and architecture. Researches and evaluates new software, frameworks and techniques to provide recommendations. Focused and driven collaborator skilled in mentoring onboarding employees and upgrading and debugging existing software. I have spent my last 2 years focusing on the backend and built lots of Microservices and Integrations. Relational Databases (Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL). Frontend (Vue, Laravel-Livewire, jQuery, JavaScript, AngularJS). Backend (Java-Spring Boot, Laravel, Adonis JS, Node JS). I would like to chip in this information, I'm down to earth with great human ad soft skills (Communication, Time management, Teamwork, Analytical skills, Empathy, and a technology enthusiast who likes to research and understand technical concepts. I do love honest feedback, challenging tasks, and correction because they let me see clearly what I'm missing and what I have to improve upon.

SKILLS

- Complex Problem Solving
- Testing and Deployment
- Project Management
- Design and Development
- Systems Administration: Windows Server 2012, Linux Environment, Database Management, Relational Databases.
- Test Planning and QA
- Time Management and Prioritization
- Web Technologies: AngularJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Vue, Laravel-Livewire, React
- Scripting Languages: PHP, Python, JavaScript, Python, Bash
- Back-End and Database Skills
- JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks
- Design Software: Figma, Adobe Photoshop, illustrator and XD
- Communication and Interpersonal Skills

- Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB
- RDMS Design
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- DevOps Engineering
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Clouds: Google Cloud Platform, AWS
- Operating Systems: Linux-based OS, Windows Server
- Backend Development: Express JS, Node Js, Laravel, OOP PHP, Oracle, MySQL, Spring Boot, .NET, Microservices, REST APIs, GraphQL
- Microsoft Office Suit: Word, Access, Excel, Power point, Data entry (Excel & Access)
- Remote access to perform troubleshooting when needed

EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer & API Tester, Africa Systems, June 2021-January 2022 Accra, Ghana

- Coded, tested and developed solutions in alignment with project requirements.
- Wrote reusable, testable and efficient code using Laravel, SpringBoot(JDBC).
- Creation of Microservices, RESTful Endpoints services.
- Testing and automating tests using Postman.
- Designed Databases and architecture. (PostgreSQL, MySQL)
- Writing backend task schedules using python, Laravel (jobs, Queues, Tasks), Windows Task Manager, Linux Cron Jobs.
- Securing microservice endpoints.

- Third-party API integration and implementations.
- Performed code review for peers and provided recommendations for improvements.
- Created security and data protection applications to secure assets.

Full stack Developer, Union Systems Global, June 2019-July 2021 Accra, Ghana

- Managed both back-end and front-end aspects of Banking Applications development process.
- Modified existing software systems to enhance performance and add new features.
- Monitored equipment functionality to verify optimal performance and adjust system controls.
- Updated software upon release of vendor patches to mitigate vulnerabilities.
- Coordinated testing and validation procedures through software development lifecycle.
- Managed 3 junior developers by delivering consistent coaching and constructive feedback.
- Collaborated with support team to assist client stakeholders with emergent technical issues and develop effective solutions.
- Supervised team of developers in analysis and creation of QR Payment System software.
- Third-party API integration and implementations.

IT Specialist, Ghana Health Service, September 2018-June 2019 Akunfudi Polyclinc, Assin Fosu, Ghana

- Procurement of Computers,
- Introduced Excel worksheet for record-keeping and efficient work.
- Database Administration
- Digitalizing data entry
- Development of a desktop application for NHIS Claims
- Responded to assistance requests from users and directed individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Assisted in technical support process refinement to improve customer service and support.
- Updated software versions with patches and new installations to close security loopholes and protect users.

IT Intern (Systems Administration), VOKACOM, June 2016-September 2016 Accra. Ghana

- Facilitated communication between departments, management and customers to resolve issues and achieve performance targets.
- Organized and maintained documents, files and records.
- Worked with management team to improve workflows and eliminate unnecessary tasks.
- Maintaining and updating of websites
- Troubleshooting computer networks and resolving conflicts
- Managing shared resources and system hardware.
- Application data entry
- Designing logos, letterheads, business cards, using designing tools: Photoshop.

LANGUAGES

English – Advance.

German - Elementary.

French - Beginner.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science

Computer Science, University of Cape Coast, Ghana May 2018

Self-Taught Software Development, Online

Microsoft Office Suite Certifications, Beacon Training Center, Accra, Ghana

High School Diploma

Accra Academy Senior High School, Accra, Ghana May 2013

PROFILES

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kwabena-ampah/

GitHub: https://github.com/khobbie

CERTIFICATIONS

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/VQSGGRLC6W8Thttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/VTQGX2Q9S6GBhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/93GN3YPWFKF7https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/9ALZ42WKYKTDhttps://www.coursera.org/account/acco

REFERENCES

Name: Mr. Derrick Osei Acheampong Company: Software Group, Ghana Title: Senior Software Engineer

Email: derrickosei.acheampong@softwaregroup.com Phone: +233248328651 (WhatsApp / Telegram)

Skype: deckhel

Name: Mr. Christian Ashun

Company: Bestpoint savings and loans, Ghana

Title: Application Support

Email: cashun@bestpointgh.com

Phone: +233207955915 (WhatsApp / Telegram)

Skype: ash11nb22